Kuldeep Tiwari

Hyderabad-500005 Mobile: +91-9340252065/7898118164 Telangana-India Email: kuldeeprewa1993@gmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To work in a progressive organization where I can fully utilize my potential and experience, which should be challenging & employee-centric, and to make a continued significant contribution appointment that offers an opportunity with a welcome attitude for new ideas and concepts to enhance the overall growth & development for the organization.

LinkedIn- linkedin.com/in/kuldeep-tiwari-53131946

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

An enthusiastic, talented professional with 4+ years of progressive industry experience in Human Resources, Staffing and Business Development. Committed to managing operations flawlessly while consistently delivering desired results and contributing to the revenue and savings-producing activities. Strong strategic planner, problem solver, and persuasive leader, Cross-functional team-building mentor with good verbal & written communication and interpersonal skills.

AREA OF EXPOSURE

Employee Life Cycle Management Payroll & HRMS (Zoho People) Statutory Compliances

Talent Management Legal & Security Management Performance Appraisal Process

Employee Relations/Queries Policy Formulation & Implementation Employee Health Ins. (Medical)

EPFO, ESIC & PT portal handling Talent Acquisitions Zoho Recruit software

and filing.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Organization : GODI INDIA PVT LTD.

Tenure : Oct-2021-Till Date

Process : HR (Talent Acquisition) & Operations

Designation : HR Generalist

GODI is an innovative organization focused on research and development (R&D), and Giga scale Manufacturing (Indigenous Gigafactory) Li-ion Battery, and Recycling of sustainable green energy storage technology.

- **Recruitment & Selection**: Managed all phases of recruitment from end to end. Handled the whole gamut of recruitments from junior to higher level (Executive to Director) via multiple channels of resourcing including job portals (Naukri, LinkedIn, Indeed etc.), head hunting, employee referrals, walk in interview, external references, advertisements, social media, third party vendors etc.
- Managing the complete life cycle of employee. (**Hire to Retire**)
- Managing all HR operational activities On-boarding, Employee Relations, Grievance Handling, Data Analysis, Attrition Forecasting, Employee Retention, Exit Interviews, Retention Talks, joining

Formalities, Background checks, Biometric access, new employee accommodation, Coordinating with admin team for housekeeping & contract employee's benefits, weekly & monthly Reports etc.

- Drafting and generating offer letters & appointment letters.
- Maintaining ZOHO HRMS tools (Employee Leaves, attendance, holidays, PMS, goals etc.) HRIS
 Dashboards & ERP, creation and maintenance of databases and other related reports like employee
 master, PMS reports etc.
- Managing location leave & attendance data, shift allowance, special incentives, roaster, biometric activation & deactivation.
- On Boarding Process & Induction: conducting induction & Orientation with the departments.
- Payroll processing & management through payroll tools (ZOHO)
- Generating form 16 & 24Q filing.
- New member registration & filing monthly challan of **EPFO**, **ESIC**, & **PT**. (Subunit registration).
- **PMS**: Responsible & Coordination for KRA's setting, performance review, managing complete appraisal system & getting the appraisal process completed with the set deadlines, data management, letter development and distribution, salary revision, pre & post employee queries & grievance handling.
- **Policies & Procedures**: Formulating & reviewing strategic HR policies for organizational productivity, benefits & discipline. Formulating HR manuals & Handbook.
- Audits: Coordinating periodic internal and external Audits on Finance & HR Process, compliance requirements and ensure the compliance levels are met. Attending internal & external HR & compliance audits.
- Mediclaim: Providing timely input, handling Mediclaim queries, coordinating with medical representatives, organizing Mediclaim camps, coordinating with finance for the agreement renewal & payout.
- Coordinating quarterly & annual Reward & Recognition events, annual party, town hall, Organizing several camps, Employee Welfare portal/dashboards.
- Managing company's sports, Fun activities.
- Organized a few other training courses. All meets, organizing buddy meets, new joiner meets.

Organization : UOLO ED-TECH PVT LTD.

Tenure : Feb 2020-Jan 2021

Process : Development & Product Trainer
Designation : Business Development Manager

UOLO brings everyone in the education community together to help K-12 students succeed. They create technology products, content and ERP platforms that connect schools & colleges, teachers and parents to help the students discover their passion and improve their skill.

- Filling positions within an organization, Designing and implementing recruiting systems for the organization, Developing own network of suitable candidates. Job Posting, screening, shortlisting & Interview.
- Bulk sales Hiring based upon the requirement for different-different locations & ERP product training.
- ERP software product demonstration & training to new hires & clients (Online & Offline training).
- Handling employee database. Job boards (Naukri, LinkedIn etc.), working with organizations to develop a recruitment plan, executing recruitment plans efficiently.
- Lead marketing effort in developing and selling new products, improved service and sales levels with an enthusiastic team spirit.
- Designed the whole and sole sales team with refined business acumen and exemplary people skills. Facilitate a team approach to achieve organizational objectives, increase productivity, and enhance employee morale.
- Expertise in Customer Satisfaction with adjusting time limit in sales and services with administrative ability.

Organization : Super Auto India Limited : Nov 2017- Dec 2018

Process : Production

Designation : Trainee Production Engineer

It is manufacturing pressure die casting component & sheet metal. component It has a customer Mahindra & Mahindra Ltd, Bajaj auto Ltd, Yamaha Motor India(P)Ltd. & Honda Motorcycle and Scooter India (P) Ltd. manufacture vehicle.

- Managing day-to-day manpower Planning
- Daily Production analysis
- Handling and operating CNC, VMC & HCM machines
- Maintain Record
- Daily scrap analysis
- Machine monitoring

INTERNSHIP

Organization : SpeedLabs Ed-Tech Pvt Ltd.

Tenure : July 2021-Sep 2021

Process : Recruitment
Designation : HR Recruiter

- Job Posting in Naukri, LinkedIn, indeed portals.
- Resume Screening/Shortlisting & bulk hiring.
- Phone call interviews.
- Conducting Interviews.
- Coordinating Interview with managers.
- Induction.
- Conducting training session for new joiners.

Organization : Reliance Retail Pvt Ltd.
Tenure : Feb 2021-June 2021

Process : Recruitment

Designation : HR Recruiter & Coordinator

- Job Posting
- Resume Screening/Shortlisting & bulk hiring.
- Phone call interview
- Coordinating Interview with managers
- Induction Coordination.
- Onboarding new employee in Reliance HRMS

- Background Verification & Document Verification
- Handling Reliance HRMS software for pre-onboarding and post-onboarding for new candidates.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

- MBA (Human Resource Development) from APS University 70.8%
- B.E. (Mechanical) From RGPV Bhopal– 66.8%
- 12th MP Board, Bhopal 81.6%
- 10th- MP Board, Bhopal 78.16%

SKILLS & SOFTWARE

- Job Posting, Recruitment Onboarding, Offboarding Joining Formalities. Employee Relations & Coordination Salary Negotiation, Benefits & Health Insurance Statutory Compliance Attendance & Leave Management Performance management & Appraisal HR Policies Implementation HR Operations HRMS handling. EPFO, ESIC & PT portal handling (filing). Bulk & Lateral Hiring.
- Zoho HRMS. Zoho Payroll, Zoho People (HCM), Reliance HRMS, HRIS, Microsoft Office (Excel, PowerPoint & MS-Word), Outlook (Visio, Share point, Forms, OneDrive, Google Sheet etc.)

Certifications

- Diploma Course in Labour Law & Statutory Compliance from UDEMY (UC-fc774e22-5567-4d42-9714-135a9adcc61b)
- The fundamentals of digital marketing- Google Digital Garage (53B 684 FT6)
- Performance management and competency mapping- Globsyn Business School Online (GBSO-003-2020-5967)
- Onboarding New Hires as a Manager- LinkedIn

Hobbies:

- Cooking
- Travelling
- Gardening.

PERSONAL PROFILE

Nationality : Indian

Language : Hindi (Professional), English (Professional), Marathi (Conversational)

Permanent Address : Rewa, Madhya Pradesh Contact no. : +91-9340252065/7898118164. Email : kuldeeprewa1993@gmail.com